# **Hong Phung Phat**

## **Senior Software Developer**

30 Sep 1992 201/1/4 Doi Cung, W.9, D.11 HCMC. 0764 74 99 64 (Phone/Zalo/WhatsApp)

hpphat1992@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hpphat1992/



# **Summary**

Senior Web Developer specializing in front-end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects in many scopes (social networks, data management, travelling, ...). Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML5, JavaScript, CSS. Have strong background in some common Web frameworks and libraries such as AngularJS, Angular, ReactJS... The target is to become a full stack developer or a tech-lead.

# **Experience**

# Senior Software Engineer

Backbase - R&D AI Team - Hybrid - District 3 - HCM

Nov 2024 - Present

- Collaborate closely with project managers and the AI team to develop and implement AI-powered solutions for the banking sector.
- Implement ideas and ensure it is following the release schedule.

**Key achievement**: Worked as part of an R&D team in a product-focused company, where the process and workflow emphasized innovation and idea development over traditional delivery timelines.

### Senior Software Engineer

HCL Technologies Limited - Remote - District 1 - HCM

Dec 2021 - Nov 2024

- Work with a team from a multi-country company to develop a DMS for managing documents of whole aerospace company using technologies: Angular 11-14, GoJS.
- Joining meetings in the Agile/Scrum process to understand, report and contribute to the development process..
- Raising some new ideas to improve the current UI/UX of the application.

**Key achievement**: Learn a new scope of business in managing the documents. Work with other team members from other countries with different countries and timezones.

# Senior Software Engineer

Saigon Technology Solution - Hybrid - Tan Binh - HCM

Oct 2020 - Dec 2021

- Work in a team to develop a wealth management application using Angular, Ruby on Rails, SOLID principles.

- Joining meetings in the Agile/Scrum process.
- Contribution in the development process.

**Key achievement**: Have some contribution in the working process and code quality improvement.

## Senior Software Engineer

Nashtech Vietnam - Onsite - Tan Binh - HCM

Dec 2018 - Oct 2020

- Joined the team to develop a web application for the wealth management domain of a bank.
- Joined meetings and followed the Agile/Scrum process.
- Using modern technologies at the running time: Kendo UI, moment, lodash.

**Key achievement**: Learned many new things from new business scope in wealth management and Agile/Scrum process.

## Software Engineer

New Ocean Information System Co., Ltd - Onsite - Tan Binh - HCM

Sep 2014 - Dec 2018

- Joined a team to develop an application based on Qt to send and receive data on a big network.
- Joined a team to develop applications using modern technologies at that time (AngularJS, Angular, Reactjs).

Web

AngularJS, ReactJS...

Frameworks/Libraries:

Angular,

- Helped to support other teams to review code.
- Helped companies train for new comers.

Key achievement: Archived knowledge of web development and had some basic knowledge on Javascript.

**Education** Skills

**Bachelor of Computer Science - Computer Vision** 

University of Science, Ho Chi Minh, Viet Nam.

2010 - 2014 Work Process: Agile/Scrum

# **Key Projects**

### Backbase - Backbase

Nov 2024 - Now

Working on the R&D department to implement the new Al-based ideas to collaborate the the main product of company.

Mainly Scope: Banking

<u>Technologies</u>: Angular, Bootstrap, Jest <u>Environment</u>: Webstorm, Github, Nx

Role: Front-end Developer.

### Statrys - HCL

Sep 2022 - Nov 2024

Building the application for both Front users and admin user of a fintech company to allow user to make a money transfer in different currencies.

Mainly Scope: FinTech

Technologies: Angular, ReactJS, TailwindCSS, Material, GraphQL, Unit testing using Jasmine/Karma,

Environment: VSC, Git, Chrome, Windows, Agile/Scrum

Role: Front-end Developer.

### PW - HCL

Dec 2021 - Dec 2023

Develop a DMS system for storing the document regarding to aerospace scope

Mainly Scope: Aerospace, DMS

Technologies: Angular 11-14, GoJS, ASP NET

Environment: Webstorm, Git, Chrome, Windows, Agile/Scrum, Remote Desktop Connection

Role: Front-end Developer.

### **Finantix - Nashtech**

Dec 2018 - Oct 2020

An applicant for manage the orders/invoices/payments. Also, other bankers, or wealth managers can use to introduce / demonstrate the plan to customer.

*Mainly Scope*: ODC – Finance, Banking, Insurance, Wealth management.

<u>Technologies</u>: Angularjs, Angular 7, Nodejs, IOS (Swift), Android (Java), SOLID principles.

Environment: Webstorm, Git, Chrome, IOS, Android, MacOS, Agile/Scrum.

Role: Front-end Developer, Mobile App Developer (Minor)

### Trabble – chatbot

Feb 2018 -Oct 2018

A project to build a chat-bot for tourism to be able to understand about the destination (famous places, restaurants, hotels) in Singapore

Technologies: HTML, CSS, Angular 5, ReactJS, Nativescript, SignalR, ASP Net core. Facebook API, Google Place API.

Angular Material, Nodejs

Environment: Webstorm, Git, Chrome, Angular Cli, Azure portal, Invision, Trello

Role: Front-end and Back-end developer.

### DMS - IMS - AMS

Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

Manage the documents which use Leaflet so display satellite data

Mainly Scope: Network Management

<u>Technologies</u>: HTML, CSS, jQuery, AngularJs 1.x, KendoUI, Leaflet, SOLID principles.

<u>Environment</u>: Webstorm, Git, Chrome, Webpack. <u>Role</u>: Front-end: Building UI, logic, Fixing bugs.

### **Sift Security**

May 2015 - Jun 2016

A page for managing devices in a network as well as using machine learning for detecting anomaly connections via a graphic instance.

Mainly Scope: Network Management

<u>Technologies</u>: HTML, CSS, D3js, jQuery, AngularJs 1.x, Angular UI (Bootstrap, Route), Lodash, Scala, Protractor, Karma,

ChaiJS, Sinon

**Environment**: Webstorm, Git, Chrome, Grunt.

Role: Front-end: Working in team to build UI, logic, binding data, writing unit test, end-to-end test.

### **Cobb and Coach Office**

Oct 2014

This page is a back-office project used to manage all the aspects of an oversea transport services company including customers management, quotations, orders, payrolls, etc.

Mainly Scope: Transport Management

Technologies: HTML, CSS, jQuery, AngularJs 1.3, Angular UI Bootstrap, Underscore, ASP.NET

Environment: Visual Studio, Firefox, SVN, Git.

*Role*: Develop front-end side (building UI, logic, data, fixing bugs) and back-end developer for fixing bugs and writing APIs.

There are also some projects that work for short terms and are not listed in the CV.